We're going to take a minute to let our brains chill out.
我们将花一分钟时间让大脑放松一下
Learning requires active engagement of your brain and really your whole self,
学习需要一直用大脑思考 并且整个身心都要投入进来
and research shows that giving yourself adequate time to
研究表明 充分休息和恢复身心
rest and recuperate helps your new knowledge put down roots,
能够加深对新知识的印象
so you can use it effectively in the future.
并且以后能够有效利用这些新知识
Getting enough sleep, spacing your learning out throughout
睡个好觉 将学习计划分散到一周内
your weekly schedule rather than trying to do it all in one chunk,
而不是一次性学完很多内容
and giving yourself permission to take a break when you feel tired or
感到疲倦时就好好休息一下
frustrated can all help you maintain your motivation and your brain's learning readiness.
这些方法都能保持学习动力 使大脑更加清醒
Meditating is another great way to take
冥想是让大脑放松的另一种方式
a mental break from learning indirect the world at large.
可以暂时屏蔽整个世界
So, let's try it out, nothing to lose.
我们试一下吧 反正没什么坏处
Wherever you are right now,
无论你现在身处何处
find a comfortable position to sit or stand in.
找到一个很舒适的位置坐着或站着
Try to let your whole body relax,
试着放松整个身体
and others can be a little bit tricky especially when you've
放松下来有点难 尤其是
been leaning in a very active way.
如果你一直都在繁忙学习的话
But just start by relaxing your hands and your feet,
先放松手和脚
let your arms and your legs relax,
让手臂和腿放松下来
let your belly relax,
放松肚子
let your shoulders roll up back and down,
让肩部放松下来
close your eyes or you can pick a spot right in
闭上双眼 或者静静地
front of you to just stare at in a more static way.
盯着眼前的一个点
Then just start to let your thoughts about
然后让关于学习或任何其他事物的思绪
your learning and whatever else is going on in your life fade away.
都消失得无影无踪
If it's hard to just let your brain empty itself,
如果很难放空思绪
you can instead replace those thoughts about
可以直接不去想这些事
anything that's going on with instead thoughts about your breath.
而是感受自己的呼吸节奏
So, to start to tune into how your body is naturally breathing on its own,
看看身体是怎么自然呼吸的
just noticing what it feels like to inhale and what it feels like to exhale.
感受下吸气和呼气的节奏
Maybe you're breathing more into your chest,
也许胸部呼入的气体更多
maybe you're breathing more into your belly.
也许肚子呼入的气体更多
Feel how your rib cage expands out in all directions as you breathe
当你吸气时 感受下胸腔是如何向四周扩展的
in and then contracts back to the center as you breathe out.
然后当你呼气时 胸腔是如何缩紧的
You don't have to control your breath anyway,
你不用控制呼吸
it's something that your body is just doing automatically on its own.
身体会自动呼吸
Or just a couple of moments here,
冥想几分钟
noticing that breath being still,
静静地
being quiet, and just
感受呼吸
focusing on this emptiness instead of everything else that's going on outside of you.
放空大脑 不去想生活中的任何事
Then you can gently blink your eyes open if you close them.
如果你闭上了双眼 可以慢慢地睁开眼睛了
So, congratulations, you just meditated.
恭喜你 你刚刚学会了冥想
This is something that you can use throughout
你可以在整个学习过程中
your learning experience using this video or on your own,
跟着这个视频冥想 或自己独立去冥想
and you can take it into the rest of your life as well whenever you
每当你想静下心来的时候
need a moment just to ground yourself and feel a little bit more calm.
都可以这么尝试一下
So, I hope this was helpful and congratulations on trying something new.
希望这个新的小技巧对你有帮助